Last Updated: 2019/02/14

Benjamin Salasek

Chicago, IL | BenjaminSalasek@iCloud.com | 773.682.6443 | benjamin.website/com | GitHub: BenjaminC137

WHY?

My hunger for knowledge, passion for coding and positive attitude. I'm extremely motivated and pick things up quickly.

FRONT-END DEVELOPER

Experience developing responsive web applications using JavaScript, jQuery, HTML, CSS, Angular 6, and TypeScript. Collaborates in an agile environment. Strong front-end and UI design skills. Five years experience writing Arduino (C/C++ based) software and developing electronic prototypes. Extensive researching and online courses..

TECHNICAL SKILLS

	TOOLS/METHODOLOGIES
Angular 6	Arduino Desktop/Cloud IDE
Bootstrap	Brackets
jQuery	Git-Hub
REST API	Google Chrome
	Adobe Photoshop
	Safari
	Bootstrap jQuery

Benjamin.Website | benjamin.website/com

- Created using Angular 6, TypeScript, JavaScript, Bootstrap, HTML5 and CSS3 and hosted on GitHub Pages
- This is my Professional Website which includes my developer portfolio
- Showcases my Arduino Projects

Slider Banana© (Beta) | Slider Banana (https://benjaminc137.github.io/JavaScript_play/)

- Web app game build using only HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript and jQuery and hosted on GitHub Pages
- The confluence of right brain and left brain! Try 'Rotten Banana Mode'! Only for Master Thinkers!
- 100% responsive web-design. Works on Desktop and mobile equally
- Utilizes local storage for saving score, achievements and options
- There are no assets or images! This is raw coding. Visually stunning artistic game with simple but unique gameplay

Interdimensional Things© | interdimensionalthings.azurewebsites.net

- Built an ASP.NET MVC E-commerce website for my final project
- C#, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS3, Rest APIs, MySql and Entity Framework
- APIs: Braintree, SendGrid, SmartyStreets
- Database and website hosted on Azure

Automatic Dog Feeder (Neechi Feeder) https://benjamin.website/neechifeeder

- Designed, built and coded a physical machine that automatically feeds my dog twice daily
- Used Arduino language (based on C/C++) in the Arduino Cloud IDE
- Agitation stepper motor with twisted metal agitator, servo motor with sliding plastic plate that opens to release food, lcd to display last time fed, current time, times fed today, manual feed button, RTC module for keeping real time

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Front-end Support Specialist | OpinionLab, Inc. | Chicago | Feb 2017-June 2018

Supported Customer Requests

- Modified and implemented code packages for bugs
- HTML, CSS, Bootstrap JavaScript and jQuery
- Utilized browser development tools to track layout issues and debug JavaScript content
- Implemented modifications for customers' website updates and migrations
- Managed multiple support tickets using Atlassian's Jira System
- Created documentation using Atlassian's Confluence Wiki tools
- Collaborated using GitHub repositories

Support Specialist | Verint Systems, Inc. | Chicago | July 2015-February 2017

Provided end user support for staff and customer support for our website feedback product

- System management: Microsoft's AD, Exchange, Office 365, SFB, Teams, VPN, VOIP, print server, Remote Desktop
- Customer support: modified comment cards in customers' websites
- Customized via HTML, CSS, Bootstrap and JavaScript

Genius | Apple Inc. | Chicago | Feb 2011- July 2015

Computer Technician

- Mac computer technical support
- Computer & iPhone Repair

EDUCATION & SKILLS

Columbia College Chicago: Bachelor of Arts

Coding Temple - Boot Camp 2018: .Net Core, C#, MVC, SQL, ADO.NET, Entity Framework, ASP.NET MVC, MySQL, SQL, Entity Framework, MySQL Workbench, Visual Studio

Other Skills: Adobe Photoshop, Google Docs, Microsoft Excel, Microsoft Word, Microsoft PowerPoint, Atlasssian's JIRA, Scrum, Agile,

Special Skills: Graphic Design, Woodworking, Office Foosball Champion!